Jose Gratereaux

Address: Calle H #14, Villa Marina, Santo Domingo, República Dominicana

ID: 001-1339893-7 Marital Status: Casado

Mobile Phone: 1(829) 755-3252 / Fixed Phone: (809) 372-3540

E-mail: jgratereaux@gmail.com

Github

github.com/gratereaux

Linkedin

do.linkedin.com/in/ igratereaux

Skype

jose-gratereaux

Twitter:

@jgratereaux

Facebook

fb.me/jgratereaux

Profile

Accomplished software engineer specialising in object-oriented approaches to web platform development. Extensive background in full life-cycle of web development process including requirements gathering, design, coding, testing, debugging and maintenance. Proven track record of designing and implementing flexible solutions which support the requirements of the business.

Big experience in Digital Marketing and E-Commerce, played a key role on the execution of the first online store for one of the biggest telco Company in Dominican Republic.

Strengths include:

- Object Oriented Development
- Server side Development (Back-end)
- Client side Development (Front-end)
- Database Development
- Planning and Documentation
- Software analysis
- Managing a Software Development Team
- E-Commerce
- Web Development
- Web App Security / Ethical Hacker
- System Analist
- Digital Marketing
- Search Engine Optimisation (SEO)
- Social Media & Web Strategies

Technical Development

- Programming: Python, NodeJS, PHP, Javascript, HTML5, Java
- Frameworks: Django, Express, Codelgniter, JQuery, Underscore, AngularJS, Android.
- Middleware: Apache, Tomcat
- OS: Linux, Mac OS, Windows
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, SQL
- APIs: Google Map, Facebook, Twitter, Socket.IO
- Services: XML, JSON, RestFull

Professional History

Digital Marketing Manager, Centro Cuesta Nacional — 2015-Actual

In charge to apply the commercial strategies of the different formats from the company in the Digital Charles.

- Create the Social Media Strategies.
- In charge of the investment on digital media marketing.
- Commercial digital planning, web and social media.
- in charge of the Development of Web site, Mobile App and other app.
- Handling of influencers and talents in the digital scope that they support the strategy of marketing of the business.
- Execution of the Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) plan.
- Handling the Analytics of the Website, Social Media and Digital Ads.
- Ordered to create strategies of design and development for the different portals and digital networks.

WEB Channel Manager, Orange Dominicana, DR Telco — 2012–2015

Developed the external portals (company's website and web shop) covering online marketing, e-commerce & web Development operations:

- Lead of 5 developers who work with the development and maintenance of the platforms.
- Develop and Design the Orange Web Portals (User Interface, Front End and Back end development using Python as the backend and NodeJS for real time usage.
- Designed and developed the merchandising and traffic increase plan, with a record increase in traffic and order of 300% in a 12 month period.
 Launched special web operations, such as click to call, click to chat, mobile commerce (mobile site and mobile shop).
- Deployed a Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) program on the company's main website.
- Created paid and organic traffic campaigns for the company's web shop for enhanced web analytics.

Sr. WEB Developer, Orange Dominicana — 2010-2012

- Played key role in the successful migration of the web platform.
- Gave technical direction to external developers, including 3rd party agencies who work with us.
- Complete 100% projects ahead of schedule and under budget through careful planning.
- Cut cost by advocating to the use of open source software wherever possible, thus cutting unnecessary licensing expenses.
- Develop UI and back-end of web apps.

WEB Developer, Orange Dominicana — 2008-2010

- In charge of the development and maintenance of the official site of Orange and its Intranet
- Update of the Web sites with attractive content for the readers.
- Creation of Web Apps to facilitate the search of information and the desiciones of the clients to buy product from us.

Development and maintenance of the on line store.

WEB Developer, Eras Publicity Agency — 2006-2008

Person in charge to install, to form and to program the Systems of content handling (CMS) and as well as to develop sites animated with Flash (ActionScript), HTML, Php, Javascript and the handling of servers and Data base.

OPCOM SRL - 1998-2006

Technical support, Repair and Installation of Computers, Installer of data networks (LAN, Fiber.

Education

Universidad Internacional Iberoamericana (UNINI), MDEIS - Masters in Strategic Direction Specialty: IT - Technologies of the Information

Universidad APEC (UNAPEC), BS Computer Science - Engineer in Information systems

Universidad APEC (UNAPEC), Technical Systems analyst

Other

Management by Objectives — IESA

Social Media as Business Tool - Dom Sagolla

Project Manager - Orange Dominicana

Program of Leaders SMART - Vivesmart

Certification on CMS Liferay 6.0+ - Liferay Inc.

Advance Android developer - Udacity

Ethical Hacker - Security Tester - Exploiter Co / Pluralsight

Awards / Goals

Online Forum - France Telecom Group (París Francia) 2012 Represente de Orange Dominicana

Present/display the cases of success of Orange Dominican Republic in a global event with all the Orange FT Group subsidiaries.

Fun & Passion Award at the Orange ITN Annual Event. 2010

Winner of the prize given by Orange International to the project of integration the Web and development of the E-commerce site in the company, competing against 30 countries and 140 projects.

Work References

Available upon request.